Yaqi SU

ZJU-UoE Institute,718 East Haizhou Rd., Haining, Zhejiang 17876346826 • Yaqi.19@intl.zju.edu.cn

PERSONAL STATEMENT

A junior in Zhejiang University with great passion for studying biomedical science and informatics, managed to acquire high GPA and rank first in the past 2 years. A student majored in bioinformatics and get the hang of several programming languages (python, java, R, etc.). Experience in Linux system and standard NGS bioinformatics toolsets. Experience of research for TGS data analysis pipeline construction and investigation of differentially expressed TEs between naive and primed hESC.

EDUCATION

BS in Bioinformatics 2019

Zhejiang University & University of Edinburgh, Haining, Zhejiang

BIOINFORMATICS IN-COURSE PROJECT

Database mini-project

12/2020 - 01/2020

Database and basic software development for tracking of COVID19 cases.

Web development project

03/2021 - 05/2021

A website able to discover potential mutations in certain RNA sequence data and provide information of available medicine. Mainly in charge of the web crawler and database building part.

gRNA design software development

11/2021 - 12/2021

A software for CRISPR-CAS9/Cpf1 gRNA design using FM index for optimized searching and involving off-target & on-target score prediction.

ACADEMIC & RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Wet lab skills development

06/2020 - 08/2020

Lab WANG, ZJU-UoE Institute,718 East Haizhou Rd., Haining, Zhejiang

- Learning basic wet lab skills including PCR, WB, cell culture, cell transfection, plasmid construction.
- Help lab members of literature searching and conduct simple experiments independently.

Genomics data analysis & software development

03/2021 - present

Lab W, ZJU-UoE Institute,718 East Haizhou Rd., Haining, Zhejiang

- Genomics data analysis including WGBS, scRNAseq, etc.
- Software benchmark and pipeline construction for TGS data analysis.
- Help with the development of TETGS, a software for measuring locus-specific transposable element expression with long-read RNA-seq.

UNIVERSITY SERVICE

Member of the Student Union

2019-2020

International campus, Zhejiang University

- Serve for all students studying in the international campus and organize activities.
- Collaborate with faculty & students to enhance educational and social environments.

Leader of the Student Art Troupe

2020-2021

International campus, Zhejiang University

•In charge of all daily affairs and activities of the Art Troupe.

Voluntary Association Member

2019-present

International campus, Zhejiang University

• Participate in both on-campus and off-campus volunteer activities.